<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Blog on C.O.M.</title><link>http://localhost:1313/blog/</link><description>Recent content in Blog on C.O.M.</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 20 Mar 2022 19:26:35 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Information and the History of Philosophy: Introduction</title><link>http://localhost:1313/blog/2021-06-18-information-history-philosophy-introduction/</link><pubDate>Fri, 18 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/2021-06-18-information-history-philosophy-introduction/</guid><description>This article is part of the volume Information and the History of Philosophy.
At the start of the pandemic of 2020, facial recognition systems were momentarily thrown into disarray. How to identify faces, if everyone venturing outside covers mouths and noses with virus-repellent cloth?1
That these machine learning systems could soon make do with simply people’s eyes and facial shape is, to me, telling, not just because of the nauseating extent of continued on- and offline surveillance it reveals.</description></item><item><title>Information Visualization in the Philosophical Transactions</title><link>http://localhost:1313/blog/2021-06-18-information-visualization-in-the-philosophical-transactions/</link><pubDate>Fri, 18 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/2021-06-18-information-visualization-in-the-philosophical-transactions/</guid><description>An article that discusses how information visualization functions in the Royal Society of London’s Philosophical Transactions, one of the earliest scientific journals.</description></item><item><title>Interview with Breaking the Waves podcast</title><link>http://localhost:1313/blog/2021-06-01-interview-breaking-waves/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2021 14:25:47 +0200</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/2021-06-01-interview-breaking-waves/</guid><description>A conversation with Matt Cornell on evidence of data fabrication in Dutch contact tracing, and the pseudoscience of government-sponsored Fieldlab events in the Netherlands.
Listen at your leisure.
Speak up, get organised together with neighbours, friends, family and acquaintances to take action if you think that such public health misoperations are not OK.</description></item><item><title>Data fabrication in contact tracing data in the Netherlands</title><link>http://localhost:1313/blog/2021-04-20-data-fabrication-contact-tracing-netherlands/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Apr 2021 20:35:18 +0100</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/2021-04-20-data-fabrication-contact-tracing-netherlands/</guid><description>There have been credible reports of data fabrication in contact tracing data in The Netherlands. These have potentially serious implications for public health data, policy, research and society. Data owners (RIVM, GGDs) and (re)users must investigate, notify, and where applicable, retract.</description></item><item><title>Philosophy as Work</title><link>http://localhost:1313/blog/2020-10-16-philosophy-as-work/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Oct 2020 08:52:58 +0200</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/2020-10-16-philosophy-as-work/</guid><description>A seriously tongue-in-cheeck mock-up of a philosophy job ad within the multi-level marketing structure of today&amp;rsquo;s Corporate University™, in the shape of a philosophy article</description></item><item><title>Amo and Molyneux’s Question</title><link>http://localhost:1313/blog/2020-01-01-amo-molyneux/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/2020-01-01-amo-molyneux/</guid><description>An article that discusses what the philosopher Anton Amo (ca. 1703–ca. 1750) plausibly might have said, had they considered questions about cross-modal learning</description></item><item><title>‘Data’ in the Royal Society’s Philosophical Transactions, 1665–1886</title><link>http://localhost:1313/blog/2019-10-09-data-in-the-royal-society-philosophical-transactions/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/2019-10-09-data-in-the-royal-society-philosophical-transactions/</guid><description>Introduction In an era of big data and data intensive science which, as some have suggested, may even make models, theories and hypotheses obsolete, it can be difficult to imagine that notions of data were not always already central to scientific practice.1
How did the notion of ‘data’ come to be such a core part of thinking about science? While scholars have studied the histories of various epistemic units, including facts, experience, observation and, more recently, information, surprisingly little is known about the history of the notion of data.</description></item><item><title>Philosophy by Postcard: Iris Murdoch</title><link>http://localhost:1313/blog/2019-09-15-philosophy-postcard-iris-murdoch/</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 Sep 2019 10:54:25 +0200</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/2019-09-15-philosophy-postcard-iris-murdoch/</guid><description>In 2019 I contributed a &amp;lsquo;postcard&amp;rsquo; to the Philosophy by Postcard-initiative to celebrate the centenary of the birth of writer and philosopher Iris Murdoch (1919&amp;ndash;1999).1 The idea: anyone can send in a postcard with a (philosophy) question; others write in reply. The postcard I responded to, by a person identified as &amp;lsquo;Josie&amp;rsquo;, inquired about self-love. What is it? Is it even possible?
As it happened, I had spent much of the Summer of 2018 immersed in Murdoch&amp;rsquo;s letters, and this reply is (nearly?</description></item><item><title>Inscription Rebellion on Elizabeth Carter’s (1717-1806) Title Page</title><link>http://localhost:1313/blog/2019-06-03-inscription-rebellion/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Jun 2019 20:35:18 +0100</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/2019-06-03-inscription-rebellion/</guid><description>In 1758, a revolutionary text left London-based printer S. Richardson, swiftly finding its way from booksellers in The Strand and Pall Mall to the shelves of hundreds of philosophically inclined households. Supported by over 100 subscribers in an early form of crowdfunding, here was the first English translation of the complete works of the Stoic philosopher Epictetus. Contemporary sources state that the translation ‘made a great noise all over Europe’ and it long remained a standard work.</description></item><item><title>Anton Wilhelm Amo’s Philosophy of Mind</title><link>http://localhost:1313/blog/2019-04-01-amo-philmind/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/2019-04-01-amo-philmind/</guid><description>Introduction “The philosopher”, Anton Wilhelm Amo states in his final published work, “should perpetually dwell on those things which can be known.” (Amo, 1738, p. 26) One of the phenomena that allow for certain knowledge, Amo thinks, is the human mind. The mind is the unchangeable, stable part of the human being (Amo, 1738, pp. 24, 26; cf. Meiner, 1734, p. 14). It should then be no surprise that the mind figures prominently in Amo’s thinking.</description></item><item><title>Anton Wilhelm Amo and the Problems of Perception</title><link>http://localhost:1313/blog/2019-03-01-amo-perception/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/2019-03-01-amo-perception/</guid><description>An article on Anton Amo&amp;rsquo;s (c. 1703–c. 1750) claim that the human mind does not have sense perception</description></item><item><title>Women Philosophers Get No Agency: Elisabeth of Bohemia</title><link>http://localhost:1313/blog/2018-03-20-women-philosophers-agency/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/2018-03-20-women-philosophers-agency/</guid><description>Essay on agency and the representation of women philosophers</description></item><item><title>Sympathetic Action in the Seventeenth Century</title><link>http://localhost:1313/blog/2018-01-01-sympathetic-action/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/2018-01-01-sympathetic-action/</guid><description>An article on the concept of sympathy as it appears in seventeenth- and eighteenth-century action explanation</description></item><item><title>Why Don’t Philosophers Talk About Slavery?</title><link>http://localhost:1313/blog/2017-03-20-why-dont-philosophers-talk-about-slavery/</link><pubDate>Sat, 28 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/2017-03-20-why-dont-philosophers-talk-about-slavery/</guid><description>Essay which asks why philosophers have been silent on slavery in the history of their field</description></item><item><title>Leibniz and the Ethics of Probability</title><link>http://localhost:1313/blog/2016-10-01-leibniz-ethics-probability/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/2016-10-01-leibniz-ethics-probability/</guid><description>Paper that discusses how the philosopher G.W. Leibniz (1646-1716) saw probability theory apply to ethical questions</description></item></channel></rss>