<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>data on C.O.M.</title><link>http://localhost:1313/tags/data/</link><description>Recent content in data on C.O.M.</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 18 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/data/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Information Visualization in the Philosophical Transactions</title><link>http://localhost:1313/blog/2021-06-18-information-visualization-in-the-philosophical-transactions/</link><pubDate>Fri, 18 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/2021-06-18-information-visualization-in-the-philosophical-transactions/</guid><description>An article that discusses how information visualization functions in the Royal Society of London’s Philosophical Transactions, one of the earliest scientific journals.</description></item><item><title>Interview with Breaking the Waves podcast</title><link>http://localhost:1313/blog/2021-06-01-interview-breaking-waves/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2021 14:25:47 +0200</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/2021-06-01-interview-breaking-waves/</guid><description>A conversation with Matt Cornell on evidence of data fabrication in Dutch contact tracing, and the pseudoscience of government-sponsored Fieldlab events in the Netherlands.
Listen at your leisure.
Speak up, get organised together with neighbours, friends, family and acquaintances to take action if you think that such public health misoperations are not OK.</description></item><item><title>‘Data’ in the Royal Society’s Philosophical Transactions, 1665–1886</title><link>http://localhost:1313/blog/2019-10-09-data-in-the-royal-society-philosophical-transactions/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/2019-10-09-data-in-the-royal-society-philosophical-transactions/</guid><description>Introduction In an era of big data and data intensive science which, as some have suggested, may even make models, theories and hypotheses obsolete, it can be difficult to imagine that notions of data were not always already central to scientific practice.1
How did the notion of ‘data’ come to be such a core part of thinking about science? While scholars have studied the histories of various epistemic units, including facts, experience, observation and, more recently, information, surprisingly little is known about the history of the notion of data.</description></item></channel></rss>